Contact Information

Email

kallempu@rhrk.uni-kl.de

Address

Meisenweg 8, Kaiserslautern, Germany

Phone

01625773848

Date of birth

08-27-1996

Nationality

Indian

Link

https://www.linkedin.com/in/goutham-kallempudi-412853109/

Skills

Java

Python

Groovy

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Data Analysis

Git

SOL

Haskell

Languages

English

Advanced. IELTS: 7.5/9

German

Elementary. A1

Goutham Kallempudi

Computer Science Masters Student at TU Kaiserslautern

A creative computer science master's student at TU Kaiserslautern with 2.5 years of experience in Software development and a keen interest in Machine Learning, Intelligent Systems, and Software Engineering, seeking a challenging role to showcase my talent and skills to meet the company goals.



Education

Kaiserslautern, RP *April 2021*

Masters

TU Kaiserslautern

Course Work: Machine Learning, Social Web Mining, 2D Image processing, Functional Programming, Cryptography.

Grade: 1.7 (german grade)

Bhopal, India July 2014 - April 2018

Bachelors in Technology, Computer Science

Maulana Azad National Institute Of Technology - Bhopal

Course Work: Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Compiler Design, Web Search Mining, Big Data Analytics.

Grade: 8.51 / 10

Experience

Hamburg, Germany *June 2021 - Present*

Working Student

xChange Solutions GmbH

- Developing applications with Java, Selenium, SQL Server, as well as worked in troubleshooting methods and documented solutions
- Redesigned the scraping engine from scratch, speeding up the system's performance by 50%.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.

Pune, India April 2019 - March 2021

Senior Analyst

Deutsche Bank

- Individually, accomplished the target of deploying two projects in a financial year.
- Designed and developed an automation system for reading the contents of an Image document, increasing the processing speed by 50% and efficiency to 98%.
- Created software that handles and processes live data, cutting the time by 23 hours a day and reduced manual intervention.
- Re-defined the database indexing strategy which improved system efficiency.
- Established new code guidelines for the projects to improve modularity, reliability and to decrease external team dependencies.
- Contributed to the internal machine learning team in the areas of image classification.

Pune, India July 2018 - March 2019

Hyderabad, India

May 2017 - July 2017

Key Achievements:

- · Promoted to an Associate developer role.
- Obtained a highly valued Recognition award 2020, for contributing to the strategy of Automation.

Languages: Java, Python, Groovy, C

Platforms: Robotic Process Automation, Data Analysis, Machine Learning, Web Services, Deep Learning **Tools:** WorkFusion RPA, Spring Boot, TensorFlow, Git.

Analyst

Deutsche Bank

- Innovatively proposed and implemented a pipeline for deploying automation projects to the production environment, reducing the manual effort to minimal.
- Contributed to developing a web service, which assigns servers to teams without any conflict and deadlock.
- Successfully managed critical project migration to a completely new environment.
- Engaged in many business activities across the bank, thus expanding my knowledge to suggest new automation projects.
- · Certified as an RPA developer and Specialist.

Key Achievement: Received the best employee award for the

year 2018 - 2019.

Languages: Java, Groovy

Platforms: Robotic Process Automation, Web Services

Tools: WorkFusion RPA, Spring Boot, Git.

Intern

IB Hubs

- Developed a Machine Learning model evaluation tool in Django.
- Completed a case study on pharmaceutical company data and suggested the best way and best time to produce a drug.
- Applied all the theoretical knowledge from the bachelors' studies in building an efficient and optimized algorithm for predicting the future sales of the pharmaceutical company.

Languages: Python, R

Platforms: Data Analysis, Machine Learning

Tools: Scikit-learn, Git

Projects

Indoor Positioning System Using Wifi: This project aims at locating a person in the building based on Wifi signals where GPS location is inaccurate.

- · Successfully traced a person walking across two buildings.
- Build an efficient Machine learning algorithm using SVM and Random forest with an efficiency of above 90%.
- Implemented eight machine learning algorithms, and proved that machine learning algorithms work better than Deep Neural networks when the data is limited.
- Efficiently reduced the high dimensional data into meaningful attributes using PCA algorithm.

Key Achievement: Achieved 9.84/10 grade and presented the project during tech-fest NIT-Bhopal.

Algorithms: Logistic Regression, SVM (linear and gaussian), Random Forest, Decision Tree, KNN, and Artificial Neural Networks.

Stock Trend Prediction: The goal of this project is to predict a company stock based on its past performance.

- The algorithm analysis any stock and predicts its performance for the next ten days.
- · Analyzed Amazon's stock with 85% accuracy.
- The algorithm is build considering many anomalies in the market like the kingfisher stock.
- Compared linear classifiers and proved that Support vector machines worked well for stock predictions.

Algorithms: Logistic Regression, SVM

Certifications & Courses

Machine Learning:

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/EKQ7B4YL2CE2

Convolution Neural Networks:

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/GS2TNED23LAH

RPA Specialist Certification:

https://www.credential.net/9d05a41f-3886-4a8b-9c1d-c1cb6d895582

Java:

https://www.testdome.com/cert/dde859479bb846d1bce47a705b714eaa

Object-Oriented Programming in Java:

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/BJY4N7PUEBKK

Honors & Awards

Merit Scholarship from Government Of India.

Took part in Training and placement activities at Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology - Bhopal.

Member of Go-Green forum Bhopal.